Speaker 1: is recognized. Mr. Chairman, I have an amendment at the desk. Clerk will report. Gentleman
Speaker 2: from New York reserves. Amendment to the
Speaker 3: amendment and the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. McClintock offered by Mr. Massey of Kentucky. Without
Speaker 4: objection, the amendment will be considered
as read. Excuse
Speaker 4: me. The gentleman
Speaker 1: from Kentucky is recognized to speak on his amendment.
Speaker 1: I thank the chairman. My amendment is to the e-verify portion of this immigration bill in front of us. To summarize, it says no federal benefit may be made available to an alien whose authorization to be employed has not been confirmed under the verification system established
Speaker 5: under section 274 AD of the Immigration and Nationality Act. In other words, what my amendment says
is that
If
Speaker 5: you're gonna receive, is the chamber in order? If you're gonna receive welfare benefits,
then
Speaker 6: you have to go through E-Verify.
Why would
Speaker 6: we want to make it harder to get a job than it is to get welfare?
Speaker 7: Seems pretty simple to me. Now, I've been told today that E-Verify is instant, accurate,
Speaker 7: It's a great
Speaker 6: method of determining eligibility for work that accesses existing federal databases. Well, why not use that for federal benefits? I'll tell you what I'm concerned about. When COVID struck, we sent out $1,200 checks. Thousands of these went to foreign nationals who are not even in this country. The federal government said, well, our bad. We couldn't really figure out.
who
Speaker 6: should get these checks and who shouldn't. Well, now I'm told there's a database to determine all this. So I let people know I knew somebody personally in Norway who got this check, $1,200 check. And so I blew the whistle on it, I got fact checked. Instead of saying I was wrong, NPR did an expose on it because this guy in Norway got the $600 check that came a few months later.
Speaker 6: Were we able to determine almost a year later who was
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): eligible? No, a year later, he gets a $1,400 check. Doesn't live in this country, hasn't lived in this country, does not for 40 years, does not have a green card. But he
Speaker 9: received, let's add that up, 1,200, 600, that's 1,800 plus 1,400,
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): $3,200 to a rich Norwegian.
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): because our federal government couldn't determine if he was eligible or not. Oh, sorry, we'll just put the money in the cannon and shoot it out. And if you've ever paid into social security or something, if you, we'll just give you money.
So if
Speaker 8 (higher-pitched voice): we do have a
Speaker 9: system that's instant and accurate, method of determining eligibility for work, why don't we use it for federal benefits? Sounds?
Speaker 9: Pretty simple to me, why should we make it harder to get a job than it is to receive welfare or some kind of stimulus
check? I
Speaker 9: just want people to know today that's watching this, this E-Verify system isn't going
Speaker 7: to be used to stop people from getting welfare checks that shouldn't be getting welfare
Speaker 10: checks, from stopping rich Norwegians.
who
Speaker 10: are not living in the United States, haven't lived here for 40 or 50 years from getting
Speaker 6: their checks. But it should, if we were serious about E-Verify, we would use it for that very reason. Now, now that I've made my point,
here in a
Speaker 6: second I'm gonna withdraw my amendment for two very sad
Speaker 11: reasons. The first is I think I'm gonna lose Democrat support.
And I
Speaker 11: don't want to push my luck. They've been so charitable with their votes on my amendments. I think I probably
Speaker 6: extended the limits of their charitability. I might not get all of my Republican patriots on this side of the aisle, although I feel like a lot of them agree with
me. That
Speaker 6: sounds like I'm getting a lot. Maybe I won't withdraw
Speaker 7: it, but the main reason I have to withdraw it,
is
Speaker 7: in spite of my best effort, the best
Speaker 5: efforts of my staff, I'm told that it is not crafted in a way that's germane to the underlying bill. That I'm going outside of the scope of this bill a little bit. - Just a little, just a little. - So in
Speaker 12: that spirit,
And
Speaker 12: having made my point. Will the gentleman yield? I would, if I made
Speaker 13: it. Two things. First of all, you put in that bill, I'll be happy to co-sponsor it. I think you'll have a huge number co-sponsoring it. And number two, I am so glad that you are acknowledging now that the E-Verify
Speaker 14: system is workable and necessary.
Speaker 7: Reclaiming my time,
I said
Speaker 7: that it was claimed that it was instant, accurate method of determining.
Speaker 5: I somewhat doubt the claims of government and some of my colleagues occasionally. But I appreciate the spirit of the co-sponsorship, but it's not germane,
Speaker 1: I'm told, by the parliamentarian.
So I
Speaker 1: will ask unanimous consent to withdraw my amendment. Without objection.
We appreciate
Speaker 1: the gentleman. We appreciate his amendment. He is accurate that it is not germane.